Now that we've taken the time to preprocess and batch our data,
我们已经预处理数据并创建了批次数据
it's time to actually start building the network.
下面将开始构建网络
Here, we can see the general structure of the network that we're going to build.
这是要构建的网络的整体结构
So, we have our inputs,
这些是输入
which are going to be like batches of our train word tokens,
它们是多批训练字词标记数据
and as we saw when we loaded in a batch,
加载一批数据后会发现
a lot of these values will actually be repeated in this input vector.
有很多值在这个输入向量中是重复的
So, we're going to be parsing in a long list of integers,
传入一个很长的整数列表
which are going into this hidden layer, our embedding layer.
然后进入这个隐藏层（即嵌入层）
The embedding layer, is responsible for looking at
嵌入层将查看这些输入整数
these input integers and basically creating a lookup table.
并创建一个查询表
So, for each possible integer value,
对于每个潜在整数值
there will be a row in our embedding weight matrix,
嵌入权重矩阵里都有对应的一行数据
and the width of the matrix will be the embedding dimension that we define.
矩阵的宽度是我们定义的嵌入维度
That dimension will be the size of the embedding layers outputs.
该维度将是嵌入层输出的大小
Then these embeddings are fed into a final fully connected softmax output layer.
然后将这些嵌入传入最后的全连接 softmax 输出层
Remember, that in the skip gram model,
在 skip_gram 模型中
we're parsing in some input words and we're training
我们将传入一些输入字词
this whole model to generate target context words.
并训练整个模型生成上下文字词
So, for one input value,
对于一个输入值
the targets will be randomly selected context words from a window around the input word.
目标将是从输入字词所在窗口中随机选择的上下文字词
Our output layer, is going to output the probability that
输出层将输出一些概率
a randomly selected context word is going to be the word the,
表示随机选择的上下文字词为
or of, or nine,
“the”、“of”、“9”
or any other word in our vocabulary.
或词汇表中任何其他字词的概率
We're going to be trying to predict
我们将使用 softmax 层的输出
our target context words using the outputs of the softmax layer.
预测目标上下文字词
Basically, looking at the words with the highest probability that they are context words.
我们将查看概率最高的上下文字词
Then when we train everything, what's going to happen,
然后训练整个模型
is that our hidden layer is going to form
使隐藏层生成
these vector representations of the input words.
这些输入字词的向量表示法
So, each row in the embedding look-up table will be a vector representation for a word.
所以嵌入查询表中的每行将是某个字词的向量表示法
Row zero, will be the embedding for the word the, for example.
例如第 0 行将是“the”的嵌入
These vectors contain some semantic meaning,
这些向量包含一些语义信息
and that's what we're really interested in.
我们只对这些
We only really care about these embeddings.
语义嵌入信息感兴趣
From these embeddings, we can do some interesting things.
我们可以对这些嵌入执行有趣的操作
Performing vector math to see which of our words are most similar,
执行向量运算 看看哪些字词最相似
or we can use these embeddings as input to
或者将这些嵌入当做输入传入另一个模型中
another model that works with the same text input data.
并使用该模型处理相同的文本输入数据
So, when we're done training,
训练完毕后
we can actually just get rid of this last softmax layer,
我们可以删掉最后的 softmax 层级
because it's just there to help us train this model and
因为该层级一开始只是帮助我们训练此模型
create correct embeddings in the first place.
并创建正确的嵌入
Okay. So, right before we define the model,
Ok在定义模型之前
I have a function that will help us see
先看一个函数 这个函数能够查看
what kind of word relationships this model is learning.
这个模型学习的是什么字词关系
When I introduced the idea of word2vec,
我在介绍 word2vec 的时候提到
I mentioned that representing words as vectors,
如果将字词表示为向量
gives us the ability to mathematically operate on these words in vector space.
我们将能够在向量空间里对这种字词进行数学运算
To see which words are similar,
为了查看哪些字词很相似
I'm going to calculate how similar vectors are using cosine similarity.
我将使用余弦表示相似性
Cosine similarity, looks at two vectors a and b and the angle between them,
cos(θ) 会查看两个向量 a 和 b 之间的夹角
theta. It says, "Okay.
夹角用 θ 表示两个向量
The similarity between these two vectors is just the cosine of the angle between them."
之间的相似性等于二者夹角的余弦
If you're familiar with vector math,
如果你熟悉向量运算的话
that can also be calculated as the normalized dot product of a and b.
就知道 cos(θ) 等于 a 和 b 的标准化点积
You can really just think of it like this.
可以这么理解
When theta is zero,
当 θ 等于 0 时
cosine of theta is equal to one.
cos(θ) 等于 1
This is the maximum value that cosine can take.
余弦的最大值是 1
When theta is 90 degrees or rather these vectors are orthogonal to one another,
如果 θ 等于 90 度 即这两个向量正交
then the cosine is going to be zero.
那么 cos(θ) 等于 0
So, the similarity really ends up being a value between zero and one,
similarity 是一个 0 到 1 之间的值
that indicates how similar two vectors are in vector space.
表示两个向量在向量空间里的相似程度
So, let's look at this cosine similarity function.
我们看看这个 cosine_similarity 函数
This function takes in an embedding layer,
参数是嵌入层
a validation size, and a validation window.
验证大小和验证窗口
In here, I'm getting the embeddings from the pasting layer.
从传入层级里获取嵌入
These are just the layer weights.
这些是层级权重
Then, I'm doing some math and storing the magnitudes of these embedding vectors.
然后执行运算并存储这些嵌入向量的大小
That magnitude is just going to be
大小将等于
the square root of the sum of the embedded vectors squared.
嵌入向量平方和的平方根
Then, I'm randomly selecting some common and uncommon validation word examples.
然后随机选择一些常见和不常见验证字词样本
These are just integers in a range, in this case,
常见字词是
from zero to 1,000 for common words,
范围从 0 到 1,000 的整数
and for a higher range for uncommon words.
不常见字词的范围更高
Recall that lower indices indicate that a word appears more frequently.
索引更小表示字词出现频率更高
So, I'm generating half of our validation examples from a more common range,
我从常见范围里选择一半的验证样本
and half from a more uncommon range.
然后从不常见范围里选择另一半的验证样本
These are collected in an np array and then converted into a long tensor type.
将它们放入 NumPy 数组中并转换为 LongTensor 类型
Then I'm passing these validation examples into the embedding layer.
然后将这些验证样本传入嵌入层
In return, I get their vector representations back.
获得向量表示法
So, these validation words are encoded as our vectors, a,
我们将这些验证字词编码为向量 a
and we're going to calculate the similarity between a,
我们将计算 a
and each word vector,
与嵌入表中的每个字词向量 b
b, in the embedding table.
之间的相似性
We mentioned that the similarity is a dot product of a and b over the magnitude.
相似性是 a 和 b 的点积除以大小
This dot product is just a matrix multiplication between
这个点积是验证向量 a
the validation vectors a and the transpose of the embedded vectors b.
与嵌入向量 b 的转置矩阵之间的矩阵乘法运算
Here, I'm dividing by the magnitude,
在这里除以大小
and this is not the exact equation here,
与这里的方程并不完全相同
but it will give us valid values for similarities,
但是能够获得有效的相似性值
just scaled by a constant.
只是乘以了一个常量
This function returns the validation examples and similarities.
这个函数将返回验证样本和相似性
This gives us all we need to later print out the validation words
稍后我们便能够输出验证字词
and the words in our embedding table that are semantically similar to those words.
以及嵌入表中与这些字词语义相似的字词
It's going to be a nice way to check that our embedding table
这样便于我们检查
is grouping together words with similar semantic meanings.
嵌入表是否将语义相似的字词组合到一起
So, this is a given function,
我们已经提供了这个函数
you don't have to change anything about this.
你不需要更改任何代码
Now, on to defining the model.
现在开始定义模型
So, we know our model accepts some inputs,
模型将接受一些输入数据
then it has an embedding layer,
它有一个嵌入层
and a final softmax output layer.
以及一个最终 softmax 输出层
You'll have to define this using PyTorch's embedding layer,
你需要使用 PyTorch 的嵌入层定义该模型
which you can read about here.
你可以点击此链接并详细了解嵌入层
Here's the documentation.
这是嵌入层的文档
So, the embedding layer is known as a sparse layer type.
嵌入层是一种稀疏层
It takes in a number of input embeddings,
参数包括输入嵌入的数量
which is going to be the number of rows in
即嵌入权重查询矩阵里的行数
your embedding weight lookup matrix and an embedding dimension.
另一个参数是嵌入维度
This is the size of each embedding vector.
表示每个嵌入向量的大小
The number of columns in your embedding look-up table.
即嵌入查询表中的列数
These two are the most important inputs when defining this layer.
在定义这个层级时 这两个参数是最重要的输入
So, after the embedding layer,
还需要在嵌入层后面
you'll define a linear layer to go from
定义一个线性层级
our embedding size to our predicted context words.
输入是嵌入大小 输出是预测上下文字词
You'll also have to apply a softmax function to the output,
还需要对输出应用 softmax 函数
so that this model returns word probabilities.
这样模型就能返回字词概率
So, here's the skeleton code for this model,
这是该模型的框架代码
and when we instantiate this model,
在实例化该模型时
we're going to be parsing in input values for n_vocab,
我们需要传入 n_vocab 的值
the size of our vocabulary,
n_vocab 表示词汇表的大小
and n_embed, our embedding dimension.
并传入 n_embed 的值 表示嵌入维度
So, you should be able to complete the init and forward functions for this model.
你已经知道如何编写 init 和 forward 函数
When you do that, you should be able to proceed
编写完这两个函数后
with training using the provided training loops below.
你需要使用下面提供的训练循环训练模型
I'd really recommend training on GPU.
强烈建议在 GPU 上训练模型
Training this particular model takes quite a while even on GPU.
即使在 GPU 上操作 训练这个模型也要很长时间
So, I'd start training with maybe just one or two epics for now. All right.
所以建议暂时只训练 1-2 个周期好的
So, I'll leave this as an exercise,
请完成这道练习
and next I'll go over one solution for defining a skip-gram model and training it.
接下来我将演示如何定义和训练 skip-gram 模型